# Swapnil MANE

## Prime Minister Research Fellow | Indian Institutes of Technology Jodhpur

@ mane.1@iitj.ac.in % swapnilsmane.github.io/

♥ Department of Computer Science and Engineering, Indian Institute of Technology Jodhpur, 342037

i Current CGPA: 8.60

I am working in the research group SoNAA: Social Network Analysis and Application, led by Dr. Suman Kundu at IITJ. Currently pursuing doctoral research to detect, analyze and tackle cyber-aggressive behavior on Indian social media



#### □ PROJECTS

• Multilingual ngram-based convolutional network for aspect category detection in online reviews

Multilingual Reviews | Aspect Category

Knowledge Distillation: Aggression Detection Using Mini BERT

Aggression Detection | BERT | NLP

• KnowldgeNet Relationship Classification Using a Pre-trained Model

Relationship Classification | Entity | NLP **○** I Jan 2022 - Apr 2022

• Analysis of Author's Abusive Behaviour Community on Twitter

Author Profiling | Abusive Speech | SNA

• Aug 2021 - Nov 2021

 Contextual Journal Recommendation and Query Search Engine Using Word **Embedding** 

Context Vector | Recommendation | NLP

• Aug 2021 - Oct 2021

• Polarity based Sarcasm Detection using Semigraph Sarcasm Detection | Semigraph | NLP

♠ ☑ Aug 2020 - Mar 2021

 Thematic context vector association based on event uncertainty for twitter **○** ☑ Jul 2020 - Aug 2020 Context Vector | Twitter | NLP

• Effective Feature Extraction for Intrusion Detection System using

Non-negative Matrix Factorization and Univariate analysis

Effective Feature extraction IDS

**O I** Jul 2020 - Nov 2020

### JOURNALS AND CONFERENCES

2021 Mane S., Khatavkar V., Researchers eye view of sarcasm detection in social media textual content, International Journal of Creative Research Thoughts (IJCRT), ISSN:2320-2882, Volume.9, Issue 8, pp.150-157, August 2021.

2021 Mane S., Khatavkar V., Researchers eye-view of sarcasm detection in social media textual content. In International Conference on Computing and Applied Engineering (ICCAE2021) [Presented]

2021 Mane S., Khatavkar V., Effective feature extraction for intrusion detection systems using non-negative matrix factorization and univariate analysis. In International conference SACAIM 2021 [Presented]

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

2021 Applied Natural Language Processing, NPTEL

2021 Deep Learning, NPTEL

2018 Data Science Professional, Coursera

2018 NLP - Natural Language Processing with Python, Udemy

2018 Python for Data Science and Machine Learning Bootcamp, **Udemy** 

2018 Prepare Manuscript, Elsevier

2018 Python (Basic), HackerRank

2018 Data Science using Python, MITU Skillologies

2018 Programming, Data Structure And Algorithms Using Python, NPTEL

### **66 REFERENCES**

• Dr. Suman Kundu, Assistant Professor, CSE, IIT Jodhpur @ suman@iitj.ac.in

Dr. Rajesh Sharma, Associate Professor, CSE, University of Tartu, Estonia @ rajesh.sharma@ut.ee

• Dr. Lipika Dey, Chief scientist, TCS Research and Innovation @ lipikadey@gmail.com

#### **EDUCATION**

M.Tech - Computer Engineering

College Of Engineering, Pune (COEP).

**2019 - 2021** i CGPA: 8.60

**B.Tech - Computer Science and Engineering** Rajarambapu Institute of Technology (RIT), Islampur.

**2015 - 2019** 

i CGPA: 7.22

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Indian Institute of Technology, Jodhpur

**Teaching Assistant** 

🛗 August 2021 - Present

Keydabra Inc.

Data Scientist Engineer, Atlanta, U.S.

## April 2021 - July 2021

College of Engineering, Pune

**Teaching Assistant** 

math August 2019 - July 2021

**OneDot Enterprises Private Limited** 

Data Science Intern

## June 2020 - August 2020

#### **P** AWARDS AND RECOGNITIONS

2022 Prime Minister Research Fellowship Ministry of Education, Government of India

2019 Excellence Award

Department of Computer Science and Engineering, RIT among 120 students

2019 Best Student of the Year Award RIT among 1000 students

2018 First in coding competition CODE-IT, PVPIT

2018 Best Drama Director Award

Purushottam Karandak Kolhapur division, maharashtra

#### **ACTIVITIES AND MEMBERSHIPS**

2022 Member of Institution of Engineering and Technology (IET) Pune.

2021 Talk on "Basics of Machine Learning" Pimpri Chinchwad Polytechnic College Pune.

2019 Student cultural representative Rajarambapu Institute of Technology Islampur.

2020 Member of Indian Society for Technical Education (ISTE) Pune.